<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xrl | XRL</title>
    <link>https://xr-lab.org/tags/xrl/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://xr-lab.org/tags/xrl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>xrl</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://xr-lab.org/img/logo/xrl_black.png</url>
      <title>xrl</title>
      <link>https://xr-lab.org/tags/xrl/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychophysical Effects of Experiencing Burning Hands in Augmented Reality</title>
      <link>https://xr-lab.org/publication/eckhoff_eurovr_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xr-lab.org/publication/eckhoff_eurovr_20/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can interactive Augmented Reality (AR) experiences induce involuntary sensations through additional modalities? In this paper we report on our AR experience that enables users to see and hear their own hands burning while looking through a Video See-Through Head-Mounted Display (VST-HMD). In an exploratory study (n=12, within-subject design), we investigated whether this will lead to an involuntary heat sensation based on visual and auditory stimuli. A think-aloud-protocol and an AR presence questionnaire indicated that six out of twelve participants experienced an involuntary heat sensation on their hands.
Despite no significant change of perceived anxiety, we found a significant increase in skin conductance during the experiment for all participants; participants who reported an involuntary heat sensation had higher skin conductance responses than participants who did not report a heat sensation. Our results support our initial hypothesis as we found evidence of cross-modal audiovisual-to-thermal transfers. This is an example of virtual synaesthesia, a sensation occurring when single-modal (or multi-modal) stimulus sets off the simultaneous sensation over other senses&amp;mdash;involuntarily and automatically. We believe that our results contribute to the scientific understanding of AR induced synaesthesia as well as inform practical applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Perceptual and Cognitive Effects of Extreme Augmented Reality Experiences</title>
      <link>https://xr-lab.org/publication/eckhoff_ismar_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://xr-lab.org/publication/eckhoff_ismar_19/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We will investigate perceptual and cognitive responses of users of several extreme Augmented Reality experiences on an Optical See-Through Head-Mounted Display (a). They will see their hands: on fire (b), being covered by dirt &amp;copy;, affected by arthritis (d), a wound (e), and applied with virtual bandage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this proposed Ph.D. research, we are aiming to create several extreme Augmented Reality (AR) that evoke measurable physiological and neurological responses in the human brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These experiments will run on a platform capable of tracking the user’s body and recreating a volumetric representations of it. On a Head-Mounted Display, we will overlay real-time photo-realistic stereoscopic graphics on the user’s body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To investigate our hypotheses, we will build a set of systems each capable of measuring various biomarkers, including cardiac biomarkers, skin conductance, muscle tension, electroencephalogram (EEG) and hormone levels. Additionally, we will use questionnaires and think aloud protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This research allows insights into the perceptual and cognitive effects unique to AR experiences that can’t be reproduced in VR. These insights are from a highly significant clinical interest in psychology, possibly capable of creating new non-invasive ways of treating or accelerating the therapy of many diseases; e.g., mental disorders such as phobias or Obsessive-Compulsive disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
